Register of the Kenyan Subject Collection, 1950-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Kenyan Subject Collection,
1950-2001
XX798
6 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 phonotape cassette (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Bulletins, press releases, reports, pamphlets, other printed matter, and seminar papers, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Kenya.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Kenya--Politics and Government; Kenya--Economic conditions; Kenya--Social conditions; Kenya; Africa; Phonotapes
Series Description
- Subject File, 1950-1955 (Box 1.-3.)
  Bulletins, clippings, communiques, government publications, memoranda, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter, reports, seminar papers and statements relating to economic, political and social conditions in Kenya
- Drought and Famine, 1974-1977 (Box 3.)
  Printed matter and speech relating to drought and famine in Kenya
- Revolutionary Movements, 1988 (Box 3.)
  Press releases and statements relating to revolutionary movements in Kenya
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after February 1995
- SUBJECT FILE, 1950-1995
  - General (Box 1.)
  - Agriculture
  - Economics
    - General
    - Economic development
    - Industrial courts
    - Investment
    - Kenya We Want Convention. Conference on social and economic development in the emerging Kenya nation, 1963
    - Labor relations
    - Seminar papers
    - Trade
  - Education (Box 2.)
  - Environment
  - Health
    - Acquired Immune Deficiency System (AIDS)
    - Family Planning
  - History
  - Media
  - Organizations
    - General. Non-government organizations
    - Political and human rights
      - General
      - Committee for the Release of Political Prisoners in Kenya
      - Ngugi Defence Committee
  - Politics and government
    - General
    - Constitution
    - Kenya Gazette Supplement
    - Kenyatta, Jomo
    - Maathai, Wangari
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs. Statements
    - Ministry of Health
    - Socialism
  - Religion
  - Social development
  - Tourism (Box 3.)
  - United Nations
  - Women
- DROUGHT AND FAMINE, 1974-1977
  - Drought and Famine, 1974-1977
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1988
  - Union of Patriots for the Liberation of Kenya (MWAKENYA)
  - United Movement for Democracy in Kenya (UMOJA UK)
- Incremental materials (Box 4-7)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.